This house looked like an easy target, until they found what was inside.
Don't Breathe is a horror, thriller, crime film directed by Fede Álvarez.
A group of teens break into a blind man's home thinking
they'll get away with the perfect crime.
They're wrong.
The Blind Man, played by Stephen Lang.
Rocky, played by Jane Levy.
Alex, played by Dylan Minnette.
Money, played by Daniel Zovatto.
Diddy, played by Emma Bercovici.
Cindy, played by Franciska Törőcsik.
Don't Breathe is a 2016 American horror thriller film co-produced and
directed by Fede Álvarez, who co-wrote it with Rodo Sayagues.
It is the first installment in the Don't Breathe franchise.
The film stars Jane Levy, Dylan Minnette, Daniel Zovatto, and Stephen Lang, and focuses on three home
intruders who find themselves trapped and hunted in the home of their blind target.
The project, originally titled A Man in the Dark, was announced in early 2014,
with Álvarez directing, Sayagues writing, and Levy starring.
In contrast to his previous work on Evil Dead (2013), Álvarez decided the project would have less blood, an original
storyline, more suspense, and no dependence on supernatural elements—which he felt were overused.
Principal photography began in June 2015, and wrapped in July in Detroit.
Don't Breathe premiered at South by Southwest on March 12, 2016, and was
theatrically released on August 26, by Sony Pictures Releasing.
The film grossed over $157 million worldwide and
received positive reviews from critics.
A sequel, Don't Breathe 2, was released in August 2021.
The film explores themes of kidnapping, thief, blind, held captive, break in.
The tone is dark and intense.